Summary

I have extensive experience in non-profit and for-profit open source.

Program management, operations, and strategic support for open source consortia.

Background in business and tech, including management, strategy, and M&A.

Extensive experience with the business, legal, and practical aspects of open source.

EXPERIENCE

The Linux Foundation

2018 - present

Program Director, LF Projects

- Managing the human elements of the processes that ensure sustainable OSS ecosystems.
- Supporting and guiding projects at all stages of their lifecycles.
- Managing governing boards and relationships with members, maintainers, and developers.
- Coordination between OSS projects and Linux Foundation legal, finance, and IT teams.
- Managing and mentoring a team of LF Program Managers and Project Coordinators.

Supported projects

- OpenJS Foundation
- Confidential Computing Consortium
- R Consortium
- GraphQL Foundation
- Presto Foundation
- CHIPS Alliance
- Urban Computing Foundation
- Continuous Delivery Foundation
- Tizen

Samsung Electronics

2015 - 2018

Director, Open Source Engineering and Strategy

Sr. Manager, Open Source Engineering and Strategy

Manager, Open Source Engineering and Strategy

Sr. Open Source Strategist

- Managed maintainers of strategic OSS projects, achieved 5x average upstream contributions.
- Advised on open source license compliance and remediation, and other emergent issues.
- Developed structured process for evaluating new open source consortium proposals.

The Linux Foundation

2011 - 2015

2006 - 2011

Director, Client Services

Sr. Client Services Manager

Operations Manager

- Managed Tizen project, including finances for \$5M annually invested capital, worldwide trademark registration, and internal service delivery to projects.
- Managed all aspects of the Tizen App Challenge, a \$4M app development contest, including legal, marketing, communications, prize distribution, tax reporting, and operations.
- Other projects: Core Infrastructure Initiative, Xen Project, MeeGo, and Yocto Project.

Linux Strategy Team Market Manager

Power Systems RAS Architect and Engineer

- Worked across IBM to define, articulate, and execute a cohesive Linux strategy.
- Managed IBM's cross-brand Linux marketing messages and led sales enablement.
- Led synergy evaluation for a major M&A project.

Software

Facade

IBM

https://github.com/brianwarner/facade

I wrote and maintain an open source project that analyzes other open source software projects, providing insight into how contributions from individuals, teams, or companies change over time.

EDUCATION

Cleveland-Marshall College of Law, Cleveland, OH

2020

Master of Legal Studies

Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH

2006

MBA (concentrations in Finance, Economics of Technology and Innovation)

MS Management Information Systems

Kenyon College, Gambier, OH

2003

BA Mathematics (concentration in Statistics), Physics minor

RESEARCH

The Open Source Development Model

2011 - 2014

Organizational Participation in Open Communities

- Awarded NSF grant #1122642, funded in full during first round.
- Chapter in "Managing Open Innovation Technologies," Springer Press, 2012.

Nuclear Bio-Medical Imaging

2003 - 2004

Kenyon College Physics Department

 Developed tomographic reconstruction algorithms, designed EM reconstruction software for MIT, Harvard Medical School, MGH, Beth-Israel Deaconess Hospital, and Kenyon College.

PUBLICATIONS

Industry Publications

Open Sourcing Proprietary Technology Made Simple

- Ibrahim Haddad, Ph.D., Brian Warner

Upstreaming: Strengthening Open Source Development

- Ibrahim Haddad, Ph.D., Brian Warner

Establishing an Open Source Software Strategy: Key Considerations and Tactical Recommendations

- Ibrahim Haddad, Ph.D., Brian Warner

Understanding the Open Source Development Model

- Ibrahim Haddad, Ph.D., Brian Warner

Academic Publications

The Domestication of Open Source

- Matt Germonprez, Ken Kendall, Julie Kendall, Brett Young, Brian Warner, Lars Mathiassen
- DIGIT 2013 Proceedings, Paper 8

Open Source Communities of Competitors

- Matt Germonprez, J. Allen, Brian Warner, Jamie Hill, Glenn McClements
- ACM Interactions, November / December 2013, 54

Edited chapter in "Managing Open Innovation Technologies"

- Matt Germonprez, Brian Warner
- Available from Springer Press in 2013